（ナレーション）＜西暦２１９９年＞
＜地球は
ガミラスとの戦いに敗れ→
人類滅亡まで
あと１年と迫っていた＞
＜国連宇宙軍は　ひそかに
恒星間宇宙船　ヤマトを開発＞
＜大マゼラン銀河にある惑星
イスカンダルに→
地球環境の再生システムを
受け取りに行くのである＞
＜宇宙戦艦ヤマトは　ついに→
１６万８０００光年の
大航海へと旅立った＞
Powerful energy readings... Directly overhead!
Directly                 Above
（森雪）高エネルギー体　真上です！
ドォーーン!!
Splendid, Commander Shultz...
（ガンツ）おめでとうございます
シュルツ司令。→
これで　ゲール将軍にも
胸を張って　報告できます。
Now, we'll be able to hold our heads high before General Goer.
If that man hears this, he'll report to Lord Dessler, as if he'd done it himself.
（シュルツ）あの男の耳に入れば
すべてを　自分の手柄として→
総統へ報告するだろう。　だが→
However... This is our victory.
これは
我々が　手に入れた勝利なのだ。
Planet Gamilas
Capital City Baleras
Lord Dessler's Palace
（セレステラ　ガミラス語で）
Ilun Phezeron
（セレステラ）シュルツから総統へ
ご報告申し上げたいと→
A message from Shultz for our lord. He wishes to give a report to you.
通信が入っております。
（デスラー）シュルツ？
Shultz?
You gave him command of the Plat base, in the galactic hinterlands' Zol system.
（セレステラ）銀河辺境方面　ゾル星系の
プラート基地を→
総統より　お預かりしております。
Oh, yes... I left a brigade of second-class Gamilans
（デスラー）ああ～
確か　２等ガミラスの旅団に→
惑星テロンの討伐を任せたのだったな。
in charge of the planet Teron's conquest, didn't I?
I am Valke Shultz, commander of the armies besieging Teron, my lord.
（シュルツ）テロン攻略軍司令
ヴァルケ・シュルツであります→
総統閣下。
（ヒス）シュルツ→
Shultz, you are contacting us without your commanding officer, Goer's approval.
直属上官のゲールを差し置き→
本来であれば　こんな行為は…。
（デスラー）まあ　まあ→
Normally, this act would be grounds for?
Now, now. Let him speak, Hiss.
いいじゃないか　ヒス君。
は…　はい。
Y-Yes, sir.
Your report, Shultz?
報告したまえ　シュルツ君。
Y-Yes, sir!
は…　はい！　本日未明→
This morning, at Tam 10:06 Gamilas Standard Time, after fierce combat,
ガミラス標準時　タム１０：０６→
プラード前線基地は　激戦の末→
the Plat advance base destroyed the Teron FTL-capable spaceship Yamato.
テロンの光速突破宇宙船
ヤマトを撃破いたしました。
What of it?
それが　どうしたというのかね？
あっ　いえ…。　勝利の報告を→
Well... I wanted to report our victory to you directly.
じかに
総統の耳に　お入れしたく…。
君は　そんな
当たり前の報告をするために→
You requested my presence merely to report something so obvious?
わざわざ　私を呼び出したのかね？
I wished to provide some small additional glory
い…　偉大なるガミラス帝国の
建国祭に→
ささやかながら
花を添えるものかと。
for the Great Gamilas Empire's founding celebration...
忠節は　記憶にとどめよう。
I shall remember your loyalty.
That's enough! Be off, Shultz.
（ヒス）もういい。　下がれ　シュルツ。
Garle Dessler! Hail to our leader!
ガーレ・デスラー！　総統　万歳！
セレステラ　テロンの艦が→
Celestra, is it true that a Teron ship crossed the light-speed barrier?
光速を超えたというのは
本当なのか？
This is the first I've heard of it.
いえ。　私も　初めて知りました。
あなたも　そうでしょ？　副総統。
And you, Vice-Commander?
（ヒス）
うっ…　はっ　はい。　私も初耳で。
N-No, neither have I.
I would imagine not.
（デスラー）そうだろうね。
（２人）ふふふふっ。
Commander, what did Lord Dessler say?
（ガンツ）司令
デスラー総統は　一体なんと？
He said he would remember our loyalty.
（シュルツ）
我らの忠節は　覚えておくと→
仰せられた。
おお…。
愚かなテロン人め→
Foolish Terons.
Had they simply surrendered, they could have lived on, as we have.
素直に降伏すれば→
我々のように
生きる道もあったものを。
（玲・鼻歌）
♪♪　ふふふふ～　ふふ～ふ　ふ～ふふ
SID, overlay Alpha Squad's zone of operations.
（古代進）ＳＩＤ　アルファ隊の
オペレーションゾーンを→
オーバーレイ。
（ＳＩＤ）コマンドを実行します。→
Executing command.
I've linked geographic data with the heat sources projected to be the Gamilas base.
ガミラスの施設と推定される
熱源反応に→
地形データをリンケージしました。
ドーン！
（甲板員）バラコン！
ベント弁操作　どうなってる!?
Balance control, are those vents closed?
Boatswain!
掌帆長～！
（榎本）ふんばれ！→
Keep at it!
宇宙船で　溺れ死んだりしてみろ
シャレにならんぞ！→
Who the heck wants to drown in a spaceship? Not me!
おい　排水ポンプ　どうなってる!?
How are those extractor pumps?
We're closing this area! Hurry!
ここは閉鎖するぞ！　急げ！
うわっ！
Okay, we have it stopped here.
よし　こっちは食い止めたぞ。
ああ～…。
（衛生士）順次　トリアージして。
This wound's nothing. Just put some spit on it, and it'll heal.
（佐渡）こんなケガ
つば付けときゃ治るわい。→
Hey, Makoto!
おい　真琴！
原田さんは→
Harada is seeing patients elsewhere.
ほかで　負傷者を診ています。
いってぇ…。
（真琴）大丈夫ですか？→
Are you okay?
Stay strong! I'll patch you up right now!
しっかりして！
今すぐ　手当てをしますからね。
（百合亜）応急処置　終わりました。
First aid complete here.
（真琴）じゃあ　こっちを　お願い。
はい！
Okay, come here.
Right!
You'll be okay.
≪（百合亜）大丈夫ですよ。
≪あっ　うう…。
But how did the enemy attack us?
でも　敵は
どうやって攻撃してきたのかな？
そんなこと分からないよ…。
We don't know how!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）第三分隊　第四デッキの
ダメージコントロールに回れ。
Team 3 to deck 4 damage control.
（薮）チェック　終わったよ。
こっちは異常なしだ。
Finished the check. No problems.
Good to hear it.
（山崎）ご苦労。
（薮）なあ　山さん→
Hey, Yama, how long will we have to sit at the bottom of the ocean?
俺たち
いつまで　海の底で→
じっとしてなくちゃ
ならないのかね。
まだ
太陽系だって出ちゃいないんだ。
We still aren't out of the solar system. Will we really make it to Iscandar?
こんなんで　ほんとに
イスカンダルまで　行けるんだろうか。
（一同）んん…。
（山崎）俺は→
I will never allow another of my ships to sink.
自分の艦を　二度と沈めない。
（薮）えっ？
（山崎）この艦が
地球を後にしたときから→
Since the moment I left Earth, my life's been in old man Okita's hands.
俺の命は
沖田のおやじに預けてある。→
We'll do what we can. That's all.
俺たちは　やれることをやる
それだけだ。
（島）本当ですか？
Is that true?
（真田）ああ。
衛星を使ったビーム兵器だ。→
Yes. A beam weapon that uses satellites.
The large amount of debris made me curious.
デブリの数が多いのが
気になってね→
情報長に
スキャンしてもらった。
So I had the intelligence officer scan it.
It isn't debris. These are all enemy satellites.
（新見）これは　デブリではなく
すべて　敵の衛星でした。→
I believe they've been using the satellites as beam weapon relays. In other words...
おそらく　この衛星群を中継して→
ビーム攻撃を行っていたと
思われます。　つまり…。
（島）冥王星全体が
射程圏内ってわけか。
They can target the entirety of Pluto.
Then, if we surface, they'll just hit us again!
（南部）それじゃあ　浮上しても
敵の的になるだけじゃないですか。
（沖田十三）敵が砲撃する
タイミングをつかめるか？
Can we find the timing they use to attack?
（新見）やってみます。
偽装爆発で→
I'll try.
I hope that explosive camouflage fooled them.
敵の目を欺けていれば
よいのですが。
It's only a matter of time.
それも　時間の問題だろう。
But for now, we wait and believe in Kodai and the other pilots.
だが
今は信じて　古代たちを待つのだ。
そして　その機を逃さずヤマトは→
And when the time is right, the Yamato will strike back.
反攻に転ずる。
Hey, Nemoto...
（篠原）なあ　根本
あの山本ってルーキー→
That Yamamoto rookie's a real babe, isn't she?
結構　イカしてたな。
（ＳＩＤ）電波管制中。→
EM restrictions in effect. Communication not sent.
通信はできません。
分かってますよ　ナビ子ちゃん。
I know that, Navi-baby.
Command not recognized.
（ＳＩＤ）そのコマンドは
入力されていません。
Loosen up a little, would you?
固いこと言わないの。
（加藤）空度一切苦厄…。
（ＳＩＤ）そのコマンドは
入力されていません。→
Command not recognized.
3,000 kilometers until target reached.
オブジェクト到達まで　あと３０００。
EM restrictions lifted. Sugiyama, follow me!
（加藤・通信）
電波管制　解除。　杉山　俺に続け。
（杉山・通信）ラジャー！　ああっ！
（加藤・通信）杉山！
Roger!
Sugiyama!
Bravo 3 is lost.
（ＳＩＤ）ブラボー３　ロスト。
くっ！
Guess we chose a winner.
（加藤）ここが　本命ってわけか。
テロンの戦闘機だと？　どこだ!?
Teron fighters? Where?
（ヤレトラー）第１３７環境改造用→
Above the 137th Unmanned Environmental Modification Plant.
無人プラント　上空です。
（ガンツ）環境プラントだと？
The Environmental Plant?
現在　防衛システムが迎撃中。
The AA System is engaging them.
（ヤレトラー）どうやら　ほかにも
何機か忍び込んでいるもようです。
It appears there are several others hiding as well.
（シュルツ）おそらく
ヤマトの生き残りだろう。→
Probably survivors from the Yamato. Launch the interceptors!
直ちに　迎撃機を発進させろ！
（ヤレトラー）はっ！
Yes, sir.
Beautiful...
きれい…。
This is Bravo 1. EM restrictions lifted. I've found the Gamilas base!
（加藤・通信）こちら　ブラボー１。
通信管制　解除。→
ガミラス基地を発見！
Let's go, Yamamoto.
行くぞ　山本。
（玲・通信）待ってください！
Wait!
ん？　どうした？
（玲・通信）２時の方向を。
What is it?
Two o'clock.
２時？
Two o'clock?
（相原）
ブラボー１　加藤より入電。→
Message from Bravo 1, Kato.
交戦中の目標は　オブジェクト５。
He has engaged target object 5.
So that's their base?
（島）そこが　ヤツらの基地か。
（太田）座標　確認した。
Coordinates confirmed.
うむ。
ですが　まだ→
But we aren't sure it's the enemy base.
敵基地と　特定できたわけでは…。
Even if it's uncertain, you can't win some wars without placing a bet.
たとえ　不確かでも
それに懸けねば　勝てぬ戦もある。
Weapons Officer, load missiles. Prepare to launch.
砲雷長　ミサイル装填。
発射準備に入れ。
（南部）ミサイル発射準備。
機関長。
Preparing to launch missiles.
Engine Officer...
Engine on line. We can reach max speed whenever you like.
（徳川）機関正常。
いつでも　最大出力で回せます。
Boatswain, how are the Wave Motion Shields?
掌帆長　波動防壁はどうか？
We've done what we can. Inertial control is also on line.
（榎本）応急処理　完了。
慣性制御もいけます。→
これで
地べたに足着けて　戦えますよ。
Now we can fight with our feet on the ground.
全艦に達する。　こちら　艦長だ。
Attention, all crew. This is the captain.
We now move to undersea operations, to counterattack the Gamilans.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　本艦は
これより　潜水艦行動に移行。→
ガミラスへの反攻に転ずる。→
総員　第三種戦闘配備。
All crew to combat station 3.
Get the engine running!
（山崎）機関　回せ！
（薮）よっしゃ～！
Yes, sir!
Spin the trim. Blow the main tank. Raise bow thirty-five degrees.
ツリム反転。　メインタンクブロー。
上げ舵３５度。
Raise the Yamato!
ヤマト浮上！
The enemy came from within the auroras. Meaning...
敵機は　確かに　オーロラから。
だとしたら…。
ビィー
（ＳＩＤ）警告。　警告。→
Warning! Warning!
センサーが　解析不能の
エネルギー放射を感知。→
Sensors are indicating an unreadable energy emission.
警告。　警告。
Warning! Warning!
ビィー　ビィー　ビィー　ビィー…
なんだ!?
What?
（玲）うっ…。
んん…　あっ！
That's...
これは…。
Lieutenant Kodai!
（玲・通信）古代一尉！
間違いない→
This is it. This is definitely the enemy base!
こっちが基地だったんだ。
（兵）レーダーに反応。
敵戦闘機　基地上空に侵入。
Signal on radar. Enemy fighters above base.
バカな！　遮蔽フィールドは
どうなっている!?
Impossible! What happened to the concealment field?!
正常に　作動しています。
It's functioning properly.
C-Commander...
し…　司令…。
うろたえるな　ガンツ。
Remain calm, Ganz. Ship-borne planes are nothing to fear.
艦載機など　恐るるに足りん。
バババババッ…
ドォーーン！
（玲）いっけ～！
ピピピ…　ピッ
Go!
ドーン！
ピピピ…　ピッ
遮蔽システムに　直撃弾。
フィールド　消失します。
Direct hit on concealment system. Field dissipating.
んん…。
（兵）遮蔽フィールド　ロスト。
Concealment field lost.
（兵）ヤマト沈没海域に
浮上する物体あり。
Something surfacing at location where the Yamato sank.
なんだと!?
What?!
（ガンツ）この潜水艦は　一体…。
What is that submarine?
You can't tell? That's the Yamato!
見て分からんのか!?
これは　ヤマトだ！
えっ？
くっ！
What should we do? We've already given our report to Lord Dessler.
どうする？　デスラー総統には→
もう報告してしまったのだぞ。→
おのれ　ヤマトめ…。
Damn you, Yamato...
Prepare to fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
反射衛星砲　発射準備！
Preparing to fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon.
（兵）反射衛星砲　発射準備。
（兵）中継衛星を選択。
Select relay satellites.
（兵）中継衛星　選択。　６号→
Selecting relay satellites... 6, 33, 28, 57...
３３号　２８号…。
どうということはない。
It's irrelevant. We'll simply sink it again.
沈めればいいのだ。
Our report was merely a bit early... Nothing more.
報告が　少々早すぎた…　ただ→
それだけのことだ。
We will now begin our attack.
（相原）
これより　攻撃を開始する。→
ブラボー１は
直ちに　現空域より離脱せよ。
Bravo 1, withdraw from the area.
（加藤）
ったく…　軽く言ってくれるぜ！
It's not that easy!
Bravo 1, come in!
ブラボー１　応答せよ。
（通信）こちら　アルファ１　古代。
ヤマトへ支援要請。→
This is Alpha 1, Kodai. Requesting backup from the Yamato.
アルファ１は
偽装した敵基地を発見した。→
Alpha 1 has discovered the camouflaged enemy base.
こちらの装備では　殲滅は困難。
Using the equipment on board, it will prove difficult to destroy.
（南部）そっちが　本当の基地か。
So that's the real base?
（通信）よくやった　古代。
艦長。
Well done, Kodai.
Captain...
（通信）そこから
ビーム砲台らしきものは→
Can you see anything that resembles a beam launcher?
確認できるか？
No, nothing like that.
いえ　それらしきものは　何も。
おそらく
地表ではなく　地下か海中に→
It's probably hidden below the surface or in the sea.
隠されているのでしょう。
うむ。
Yes, that is the biggest threat to the ship.
その砲台が
本艦にとっての最大の脅威だ。
古代　山本は　現空域にとどまり→
Kodai, Yamamoto are to stay in the area, to confirm location.
その所在位置を　確認せよ。
Confirm it? But how?
確認ですか？
しかし　どうやって…。
（通信）目で見るのだ。
See with your eyes.
（通信）目で？
そうだ　目だ！
My eyes?
Yes... Your eyes!
（加藤）
くっそ！　こっちは　ガセかよ。
Darn it! This wasn't the right base?
（篠原・通信）そう　ぼやかない。
Stop complaining.
ドーン！
ドォーーン！
The cavalry's here.
騎兵隊　ただいま到着～。
（加藤・通信）篠原！　根本！
Shinohara! Nemoto!
And that's not all...
（根本・通信）だけじゃないですよ。
（航空隊員・通信）おら～　いけぇ！
Go get 'em!
ドォーーン！
（航空隊員・通信）ひゃっほ～！
ダダダダッ！
（航空隊員・通信）ヒュ～ヒュ～！
（篠原・通信）まるで　愚連隊だね。
いくぞ！
They look like a bunch of thugs.
Go!
（篠原・通信）ラジャー！
（根本・通信）ラジャー！
Roger!
Deploying reflectors 6, 33.
６号　３３号　リフレクター　展開。
（新見）きた！
衛星への信号　捕まえました！
There it is.
I have the satellite signals.
（真田）アナライザー。
（ＡＵ０９）解析ヲ開始。
Analyzer!
Beginning analysis.
Now deploying 28, 57.
（兵）続いて　２８号　５７号　展開。
Relay satellites identified.
（ＡＵ０９）
中継衛星ヲ　特定シマシタ。
Target locked. AA interceptor missiles ready for launch.
目標　ロックした。
対空迎撃ミサイル　発射準備よし。
Fire AA interceptor missiles.
対空迎撃ミサイル　発射！
ボゥン！
死に損ないめ…。
Last time, you survived. But you won't survive this.
今度こそ　とどめを刺してやる。
（兵）エネルギー　装填完了。
Energy charge complete.
Fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
反射衛星砲　発射！
ピシューーン!!
ドォーーン！
よし。
Done.
Alpha 2, Yamamoto, to Yamato.
（玲・通信）
アルファ２　山本より　ヤマトへ。→
敵砲台を特定。
位置　氷結した湾内。
I've identified the enemy cannon. Location is a frozen bay.
了解。　直ちに　データを送れ。
Roger. Transmit data now.
（玲・通信）ラジャー。
砲撃準備。　敵砲台をたたく。
Roger.
Prepare to fire. We'll destroy the enemy cannon.
（兵）５７号　ロスト。
洋上から　迎撃されたもよう。
57 is lost. It's been shot down from the surface.
（シュルツ）
ヤマトめ　反射衛星に気付いたか。
So, the Yamato noticed the satellite cannon.
反射衛星砲　次弾装填！
Prepare cannon to fire again!
（兵）反射衛星砲　エネルギー装填。
今度は　角度を変え→
This time, we'll change angles, firing from outside their effective range.
ヤツの射程圏外から
一撃を加えるのだ。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウウゥーー（警報）
Level the ship!
艦体　復元。　戻～せぇ～！
（太田）艦内慣性制御よし。
Inertial control working properly.
空間ジャイロ　反転。
右舷　バラスト放出。　戻～せぇ～！
Space gyros reversed. Dropping starboard ballast!
Level!
（太田）艦体　復元完了。
各部点検　異常なし。
Ship leveled. All inspections reported no problems.
（南部）
三式弾　時限信管　セット完了。
Type-3 rounds set with timed fuses.
目標　敵ビーム砲台。
Target is the enemy beam cannon.
主砲　三式弾　装填。
Load main gun with Type-3 rounds!
Ranging complete.
測的よし。
撃てぇ～！
Fire.
ドォン!!
Countdown to impact.
着弾まで　１０　９　８…。
10.
9-
8-
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（兵）エネルギー　装填完了。
Charge complete!
（南部）７　６　５　４…。
7-
6-
5-
4-
Fire the Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
反射衛星砲　発射！
ドン！　ドン！　ドン！
ガン！
ドォーーン！
ドオォォーーン!!
こちら　アルファ１。
敵ビーム砲台の爆破を確認。
This is Alpha 1. Destruction of enemy beam cannon confirmed.
We did it.
（南部）やった！
これより　本艦は→
We will now move to destroy the enemy base.
敵基地殲滅に向け　出撃する。
Raise bow twenty degrees. Launch the Yamato!
上げ舵２０。　ヤマト発進！
ドドーーン！
No signal from the Reflecting Satellite Cannon.
（兵）反射衛星砲台　応答なし。
（ガンツ）あぁ…。
そんな…　バカな！
This can't be happening...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウウゥーー！　ウウゥーー！
Yamato approaching rapidly!
（兵）ヤマト　急速接近中！
司令　ここは危険です！
脱出してください！
Commander, it's too dangerous here. Please evacuate!
脱出だと!?
生きていれば→
Evacuate?
As long as you survive, you have the chance to restore our honor!
汚名をそそぐ機会もあります。
くっ…。
測的よし。
照準よし。　空対地ミサイル→
Ranging complete. Targeting complete.
Air-to-surface missiles ready to fire.
発射準備よし。
撃ち方　始めぇ！
Open fire!
ドォン！　ドォン！
バシュ　バシュ　バシュ　バシュ…
ドォン！　ドォン！　ドォン！
ガン！
ドォーーン！
ドォーン！
ドオォーーン!!
敵艦４隻　離脱していきます。
Four enemy ships are leaving the base.
We will pursue. Switch main guns to shock cannon mode!
追撃する。
主砲　ショックカノンに切り替え。
ピシュ　ピシュ　ピシュ　ピシュ…
ビシュン!!
ドォーーン！
（ヤレトラー）
ここは　我らが盾になります。→
We will protect you. Please, be safe...
どうか　ご無事で。
んん…。
ゲシュタム航法に移行準備！
急げ！
Prepare to switch to Geschtam Navigation! Hurry!
敵艦　突っ込んできます。
Enemy is charging toward us!
行かせはせん！
I won't let you get them!
ビシュン!!
うっ…　うわっ！
ガン　ガン　ガン！
ドォーーン！
（観測士）デストリア　轟沈！
（シュルツ）うっ…。→
The Destoria has fallen.
ゲシュタムジャンプ！
Geschtam Jump!
敵艦　ワープしました。
Enemy has warped away.
The Gamilas advance base on Pluto is finished.
ガミラスの冥王星基地は終わりだ。
No more planet bombs will fall to Earth.
地球に　遊星爆弾が落ちることは
もうない。
（通信）こちら　古代。
これより　ヤマトへ帰投する。
This is Kodai.
Returning to the Yamato.
（デスラー）プラードが落ちた？→
Plat has fallen?
Hiss, was I dreaming? Did the Teron ship not sink?
ヒス君
私は　夢でも見ていたのかね？→
確か　テロンの艦は
沈んだのではなかったかな？
Yes, sir. I was given the same information.
はっ。　私も　そのように…。
シュルツは　基地を放棄。
戦線を撤退したのだな？
Shultz abandoned his base, to retreat from the front lines, correct?
は…　はい。
大ガミラスに撤退の二文字はない。
Y-Yes.
"Retreat" is not a word in the Gamilas dictionary.
勝利か　しからずんば　死かだ。
（ヒス）はっ！
Victory... If not victory, death.
Yes, sir.
Terons, huh?
テロン人か…。
（太田）ヤマト　冥王星軌道を離脱。
The Yamato has left Pluto's orbit.
（島）やったな　古代。
ああ。　やった。
We did it, Kodai.
Yeah, we did.
We did it, Brother.
（心の声）≪やったよ　兄さん≫
We will return to our original course. Set engines to combat speed 1.
これより　予定の航路に戻る。
機関　第一戦速！
（島）航路修正。　第一戦速！
Course adjusted. Engines at combat speed 1.
Episode 6: The Sun Sets on Pluto
With different emotions in each of their hearts,
the crew of the Yamato now leave the solar system behind.
Before them lies a galaxy no human has ever seen.
Say a prayer for those who set sail,
and a goodbye to those left behind.
Let your feelings be heard.
Farewell, Earth.
We will return!
Next time: Farewell to the Solar System.
There are 355 days left before humanity is extinct.
振り込め詐欺に代わる新しい名称
を
警視庁が募集していたが、
今日、そのネーミングが発表され
た。